♪ It seems today
that all you see ♪
♪ Is violence in movies
and sex on TV ♪
♪ But where are those
good old-fashioned values ♪
♪ On which we used to rely? ♪
♪ Lucky there's a family guy ♪
♪ Lucky there's a man who
positively can do ♪
♪ All the things that make us ♪
♪ Laugh and cry ♪
♪ He's... a...
Fam... ily... Guy. ♪
Sorry I'm late.
Had a family emergency
with, um... I don't know.
I want to say Chris?
Uh, I wasn't listening
super close.
Why don't you sit down
and drink beer
and tell us about it instead of
being home with your family?
Apparently, Chris and his
girlfriend broke up.
Something about her wanting
to see other people.
So the doctor says
this surgery is gonna
restore my eyesight.
What? Oh, no.
"Oh, no"?
But I thought you'd be happy,
Colin Farrell.
Oi, blimey. Uh, get stuffed.
I'm-I'm gonna see other birds.
G-Good day, mate.
Don't look. Don't look.
I think that's Colin Farrell.
And this girl
was his first love.
Poor Chris.
He was sobbing his eyes out
when I abruptly left.
First loves always
hit the hardest.
I'll say. I still remember
my first real love.
Seems like yesterday.
Why, just thinking back on her
makes everything
all shimmery and distorted.
I was working
for Federal Express,
like Tom Hanks in Cast Away.
And just like Tom Hanks
in Cast Away,
I said the words
"Federal Express"
a suspicious number of times.
Excuse me, miss. Asking
as a Federal Express employee,
may I please get a refill
of iced tea very quickly,
the way Federal Express
delivers parcels?
There was only one thing
I loved more
than corporate-branded content,
and that was my fiancée,
Helen Hunt.
JOE: Hubba-hubba.
QUAGMIRE:
Darn right hubba-hubba.
You know how most guys
want their girlfriends
to look like a pissy bird?
Well, I was living the dream.
You're 17 seconds late.
I am a Federal Express employee
who is very obsessed with time.
Well, that's my fiancé.
Give me a kiss, you
time-obsessed beardless man
who is unable to spear
a fish with a sharpened stick.
QUAGMIRE: Remember
all that stuff for later.
Mm, oh, I can't wait
to do more than kiss.
Only three more days
till the wedding.
Yep. I've got just
one last flight
across the Planecrash Sea,
and then I'm all yours.
QUAGMIRE: Little did I know.
I'll never forget
that fateful day.
Looking back,
I never should have
tried to do two fantasy
football drafts
while flying a plane.
-I ended up with four defenses.
-Ugh!
AIR TRAFFIC CONTROLLER:
FE-117,
looks like
you got rough weather.
Maybe you should just
do auto-draft
for your fantasy leagues, over.
Uh, negative, negative, Control.
I am heterosexual, over.
AIR TRAFFIC CONTROLLER: Ha.
There's that clean-shaven guy
who cannot spear a fish
with a stick
that we all know and love.
Damn it.
Too bad I'm in an airplane
and can only go
straight into a storm
and not over or around.
Wait, I think the storm
is breaking up.
I was gonna make it, but then
the plane got hit
by lightning.
Oh!
And I somehow drafted the punter
Jeff Feagles
in the second round.
Oh!
And it was all over.
I was all alone
on an uncharted island.
What could I do?
Definitely not spear a fish
with a hand-sharpened stick.
'Cause remember, that was a
complete non-starter for me.
If I wanted to make it back
to my Helen,
I'd need to find a way
to survive.
Luckily I had a whole
plane's worth of FedEx parcels
I could open and use.
Oh, please be food.
Please be food.
Oh, thank God, I'm saved.
Peanut brittle.
Aah!
"From Peter Griffin."
PETER:
(laughs) Gotcha. Continue.
QUAGMIRE:
But then I opened the most
important package of all.
My only friend on the island.
I'm gonna call you Wilson,
after Rita Wilson,
the most beautiful and talented
woman in Hollywood.
The true first lady
of American culture.
I swear, I didn't say
all that stuff just so Tom Hanks
would let us do this movie.
(grunts)
Character development.
I had been on that island
for four years.
Man, I've been on this island
for somewhere between
two and seven years.
I'm not sure which 'cause I'm
no longer obsessed with time.
That's more character
development.
Anyway, all these years later,
I still couldn't get
Helen Hunt out of my mind.
I was going nuts
thinking about her.
Oh, Helen...
Oh come on, get it together.
Think of something else.
Think of anything besides
Helen Hunt.
Oh, almost Helen Hunt.
Enough was enough.
I decided to build a raft
and get back to my beloved.
But what to make
the raft out of?
Got to be something
I can use.
What floats?
Mm, definitely not these
footballs for Tom Brady.
Straight to the bottom.
I wonder.
Aah!
PETER:
(laughs) Two for two. Continue.
QUAGMIRE:
I was able to float away
on a raft made
out of the giant joke box.
It was me and Wilson and
this one other kind of lame guy.
Boy, you hoist a sail,
then where did the wind go?
Am I right?
I just saw you
take a dump in the ocean.
I'm not really
looking to chat.
Days passed.
Wilson and I were all alone.
No drinking water
and no food, except...
Nope, not this time.
PETER:
Eh, you're no fun. Continue.
QUAGMIRE:
But then disaster struck.
Aah! Aah!
No. No! Wilson!
Eventually I moved on
and largely forgot about Wilson.
(piano playing)
Why are you smiling, honey?
Oh, I used to bone
that volleyball.
I don't remember much
after that.
Apparently I was picked up
by some cargo ship.
But then,
wouldn't you know it,
the ship got taken over
by Somali pirates.
Look at me.
We are doing this movie now.
QUAGMIRE:
Then that Somali pirate
did a bunch of stuff
and then nothing else
ever again,
and eventually I got back home.
After years and years away,
it was finally time
to see my Helen.
Oh, my God, you're alive.
I thought about you
every day, Helen.
You're the reason I stayed alive
all these years.
I never stopped loving you.
I'm-I'm sorry.
I got back together
with Paul Reiser.
What?
We did a Mad About You reboot
on Spectrum Originals.
QUAGMIRE:
Which just sounds fake.
I mean, did you watch
any of that?
Do you even know anyone who...
I-I... Like, I literally
do not know one person
who saw, like,
a single minute of that.
I'm so sorry.
QUAGMIRE:
I was devastated.
Helen was my first true love--
the only woman I ever wanted--
and she had moved on
without me.
Fortunately, five years later,
they invented
portable pornography
on telephones,
and I've literally never
thought about her since.
Well, that was a touching tale
of first love, Quagmire.
And I googled Spectrum
Originals, by the way.
Found nothing.
Zero matches.
Nothing on Ask Jeeves either,
but they don't always
have everything.
Anyway, I remember
my first love.
It's quite an interesting story.
Okay, guess
I'll be going last tonight.
This was back
in the early '60s.
I was working
at a hoity-toity camp
for rich Jewish people.
PETER:
Are you Jewish in this?
JOE:
(laughs) No.
-I was a dance instructor.
-♪ ♪
Anyway, this camp
was highly renowned
for offering exclusively
clean dancing.
You are the cleanest dancer
I ever met.
It's why we come here
every year.
JOE:
But all the while,
I was being watched
by the prettiest girl
in the camp.
Her name was Jennifer Schnozz,
and I saw her everywhere.
Seems like she was always
sniffing around someplace.
QUAGMIRE:
Okay.
JOE:
Daytimes were reserved
for clean dancing,
but at night,
someone would bring
a very large watermelon
to the staff cabin,
and for some reason,
that meant
it was time for dirty dancing.
(cheering)
♪ ♪
JOE:
We had booze, sexy music,
and because it was August
by a lake,
lots of mosquitos.
(buzzing)
My favorite partner
was Dancy McGee.
She was the best dancer
on the staff,
as you can tell
from this dance party
where she's dancing
neither better nor worse
than anyone on the staff.
But there Jennifer was again,
always with her nose
pressed against the glass,
or anything else she was
standing three feet away from.
QUAGMIRE:
Might be going a bit hard
with the nose stuff.
JOE:
Relax, she's fine.
She got a new one.
It was time to make my move.
Hey, do I know you?
Yeah.
We were both in Red Dawn
and we probably had sex on set
and then you dumped me
and now we famously
hate each other.
Oh, yeah, Jennifer.
Well, welcome
to the Poke-a-nose.
That was kind of my joke
around camp.
People loved it,
way better than my
"welcome to the Catskills" bit.
I was not invited back
to that camp.
Joe, come quick!
It's Dancy.
What's the matter?
It's-it's my jaw.
It's very clicky.
I th... I think I have TMJ.
-TMJ?
-Oh, no!
I hear that causes
mild discomfort
but doesn't otherwise
interfere with lifestyle.
JOE:
Of course, back then,
it was illegal
to get jaw surgery.
The only places
that would do it
were sketchy, unsafe,
back-alley jaw clinics.
Do you want to keep
the TMJ?
Come on, Joe.
I'm single, I'm poor,
I work at a Jewish camp
for tips.
PETER:
Ugh. Brutal.
What's three percent of frugal,
am I right?
QUAGMIRE:
Not the year for it, Peter.
But, Dancy, what about
the big talent show?
Dancy was gonna be my partner
at the camp talent show,
which is the most important
thing in this whole story.
After I get my jaw surgery,
I'm gonna be in
mouth recovery, Joe.
I'm out.
What? Then who am I
supposed to dance with?
Literally any one
of these other women
-we just saw dancing?
-I'll do it.
Ugh.
I know I've never
danced before,
but you could teach me.
All right, I'll give you a shot,
but you better not be ticklish
if I touch the inside
of your arm
during dance practice.
Y-Yeah. No, no, that-that
won't be a problem.
♪ ♪
(laughing)
This is the (bleep)
I was talking about!
♪ ♪
Wow, I guess I'm just
really bad at
you holding me over your head
while I do nothing.
Eh, keep practicing.
You'll get there.
Anyway, I like how you
always seem to drop me
into the one warm spot
in this whole cold lake.
Yeah, and I, uh, I like how
you're at least 18 years old.
Actually, I'm...
I like how you're
at least 18 years old.
Her nickname was "Baby,"
which means over 18 years old.
Anyway, we were falling
in love, but then...
-Joe, come quick! It's Dancy.
-Again?
He's developmentally disabled
and that's the only thing
he knows how to say
but still, we should
go check on her.
-(grunts softly)
-(both gasp)
It's... it's bad, right?
No, no, it's fine.
Hey, can you hang on a sec?
President Kennedy
said he's excited to show
the city of Dallas, quote,
"just how white a shirt can be."
Joe, this is serious.
My whole jaw's messed up.
I don't understand.
We sent you to the best
cigarette-smoking surgeon
we know.
But listen,
you're gonna be okay.
(laughs)
Son of a bitch!
Fortunately, Jennifer
had called her father,
who's a doctor.
Oh, dear God.
Good thing I got here in time.
Fetch me my big bag
of medical supplies
I take on vacation.
Thank you for coming,
Dr. Hartman.
Shut up. I don't like you
because you're poor.
Daddy, is she gonna be okay?
She's gonna make it.
But I blame you for this.
Because it's important
for the story
-that I blame you for this.
-I'm sorry.
Sorry doesn't cut it.
Something this terrible
calls for real consequences.
No dancing with my daughter
at the meaningless talent show.
What? No!
My word is final.
♪ ♪
JOE:
So what I'm doing right here
is I'm thinking about Jennifer
and how she's like the wind.
QUAGMIRE:
What does that mean,
"she's like the wind"?
JOE:
Just, you know,
she and the wind.
Uh, lots of similarities
there, you know.
She's very wind-like.
QUAGMIRE:
Yeah, but like,
but how, specifically?
JOE:
I mean, where do I even start?
Basically, they're like
two peas in a pod, those two.
Her and the wind.
You know?
QUAGMIRE:
No, I don't kn... You know,
you keep saying "you know,"
and I don't know,
and that's why
I'm asking the question.
In what precise way
is she like the wind?
JOE:
Well, um, like, if you picture
my heart like trees,
she blows through my trees.
QUAGMIRE:
All right, so in what way
is your heart like trees?
JOE:
Aw, look,
it's a good song, okay?!
The point is
I'm missing Jennifer,
I want her back.
QUAGMIRE:
Just say that then.
Enough with this wind business.
JOE:
Finally, it came--
the night of the big
talent show.
The show started late
'cause the grandma bragging
had gone a bit long.
(babbles)
Doctor!
Buzz, buzz, buzz, lawyer.
(babbles)
Five foot, six.
Everyone, I hope you enjoyed
the dinner of leftovers
from last year's dinner.
JOE:
I mentioned it was
a Jewish camp, right?
But now it's time
to start the talent show.
This was my last chance.
I wasn't gonna
let all those hours
of standing in a lake
go to waste.
Nobody puts Legal Adult
in a corner.
Unfortunately, this was
the Star of David Dining Hall,
so pretty much
the whole place was corners.
It was finally time
for us to dance together.
Happy 1963, everyone.
For our big finale,
we're gonna dance to a song
written in 1985.
("She Bop" by Cyndi Lauper
playing)
♪ She bop, he bop a we bop ♪
♪ I bop, you bop... ♪
JOE:
We had to dance to this song
about female masturbation
because we couldn't afford
"The Time of My Life."
QUAGMIRE:
I think you mean
open parentheses
"I've Had" closed parentheses,
"The Time of My Life."
JOE:
Sure, whatever.
The point is we danced great
and everyone
was cheering for us.
(cheering)
-Yay!
-(whoops)
Joe, come quick!
It's Dancy.
JOE:
And that's the story
of my first love.
P.S., that night we had sex,
I got her pregnant,
and three weeks later
she had an abortion.
I mean jaw-fixing.
Whatever we called it earlier.
-Well, I remember my first...
-Anyway, I remember my first...
Oh.
Think, uh, think it's probably
gonna be Peter, right?
Sorry, Cleveland.
But I remember my first love.
It was 1989,
the golden age of Hollywood.
The year of
Troop Beverly Hills,
Fletch Lives,
Gleaming the Cube,
and a hilarious new addition
to the Harry and the Hendersons
franchise.
Harry meets a girl Bigfoot?
Count me in.
PETER:
Well, that's what
I thought, anyway.
Turns out Harry
was shorter in this movie,
but he did look marvelous.
And the actress?
Oh, my gosh.
(gasps, sighs)
You know how I always wanted
to marry a woman
who looks like
the Full House baby?
Well, this was her: Meg Ryan.
Schwing!
I said, being the first person
who ever said that.
Ha, ha, that guy's
the first person
to ever say that.
Wow, you're hilarious.
What's your name
so we can tell everyone
that you were the first?
Aw, come on, guys, I don't care
who gets the credit.
QUAGMIRE:
This is making your story
less credible.
PETER:
Anyway, from the first time
I saw Meg Ryan pout
in When Harry Met Sally,
I knew I wanted to see her pout
in every movie.
And then eventually
change her face
so she's incapable of pouting.
♪ ♪
Ah, nothing better
than movie theater popcorn.
Some for me,
some for the cleaning guy.
Some for me, some for
the cleaning guy.
So, you must really
like this movie.
Are... are-are you...
are you talking to me?
I got to talk to somebody.
He's about to do
a 20-minute song parody
of the 1988 Oscar nominees.
♪ Broadcast News
to the left of me ♪
♪ Fatal Attraction
to the right ♪
♪ Here I am, Moonstruck
in the middle with you. ♪
Come join me, Peter.
It's a 1980s movie,
so there's lots and lots
of 1940s music.
♪ ♪
-What's that guy doing?
-He's ruining the movie.
Joe, come quick!
It's Dancy.
So that happened.
(laughs)
I've never heard that.
You're the first.
Peter Griffin's the first.
Aw, come on, Meg Ryan,
it's not about that.
QUAGMIRE:
Yeah, you got to stop
doing this, Peter.
PETER:
That day we talked and talked
as an unrealistic amount
of leaves fell around us.
Hey, thanks for
walking me around
in this watered-down
Woody Allen movie.
You're welcome, Peter.
But what do you think?
Can a man and a woman
just be friends
without the sex?
Oh, uh, yeah, uh, sure, yeah.
Uh, me-men and women
can just be friends.
But, like, the fourth
or fifth friend you call.
What do you say, Peter?
Friends?
-Friends with benefi...
-Benefits? No.
I was gonna say Benefiber.
I been getting wicked
stopped up lately.
-Ew.
-Welcome to being friends
with a guy, Meg Ryan.
Me and Meg Ryan
had a special connection.
I even followed her
into other movies,
like Sleepless in Seattle,
which ends on the top
of the Empire State building.
Gee, Pop, I'm sorry
I left my backpack
just laying around
at the Empire State Building,
which is an actual plot point
from the film.
Don't worry,
it's still just the 1990s,
so it's okay to abandon
your backpack
in big-city landmarks.
-(all ticking)
-See something, say nothing,
That's the 1990s
New York way.
-Hey.
Ah. This is our last chance
to look at Brooklyn
before Lena Dunham gets there.
PETER:
I also followed her
to You've Got Mail,
where I drove her little
bookstore out of business
before my big bookstore
went out of business.
Also, I DMed her on my
eight-inch-thick laptop.
As always, I wrote to her
as friends. Just friends.
It seemed like we'd be
just friends forever,
but then came the movie
that changed everything.
The most important film
of all time:
In the Cut.
Because naked!
It's just, ever since we met
you've been my best friend,
and I was always afraid
of damaging that
because I don't want to risk
this connection.
Shh. Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
Hey.
Shut up, Meg.
COP:
Excuse me, sir? Sir.
Wake up, sir.
PETER:
Turns out I never did get pulled
up into that movie screen.
I had just
Pee Wee Herman'ed myself
in the theater and fell asleep.
(snores)
Huh? What?
What's going on here?
Um...
I'll have what she's having?
And that's when my doctor said,
"You can't drink and do Ambien."
So, there you go,
my first love: Meg Ryan.
Or maybe Melanie Griffith.
You know, now that
I'm thinking about it,
did you see Body Double?
Good God.
That's a wonderful story, Peter.
I'm always happy just to listen
-and be here for you.
-(phone chimes)
Donna says hi.
Is it okay if I tell
my first love story?
If it wasn't
good enough to tell
in one of the 88 episodes
of your show,
maybe it's not
good enough for us.
Could you guys
do me a favor and laugh
like I'm telling you
a hilarious story?
-(laughing)
-See?
I get a flashback, too.
I don't see nothing shimmering.